https://option.org/privacy-policy/

Skip to content About UsFoundersAbout FoundersBooks Written by Barry Neil KaufmanEndorsementsWhat We TeachBenefits of The Option Process®The Option Process® DialogueTestimonialsWritten TestimonialsVideo TestimonialsOur Teachers and StaffOption Process® MentorsAutism Treatment Center of America®Historic Change AnnouncementSubscribe To Stay In TouchDonate Now!Programs & ServicesProgramsProgram CalendarPrograms by InterestWritten TestimonialsVideo LibraryPrivate Counseling SessionsChallenges & Practical SolutionsResourcesAudioAn Invitation to Change Your LifeBook ExcerptsHappiness HitsInspiring StoriesWebinarsQ&AArticles & DocumentsThe Emotional Well-Being QuizCD DownloadsStoreScholarships & Financial AssistanceOur Mountainside RetreatOur CampusDirectionsDRONE Tour of Our Campus!Upcoming ProgramsContact UsDonateHelp Change Lives-Donate Today!Ways To GiveMonthly Giving
About UsFoundersAbout FoundersBooks Written by Barry Neil KaufmanEndorsementsWhat We TeachBenefits of The Option Process®The Option Process® DialogueTestimonialsWritten TestimonialsVideo TestimonialsOur Teachers and StaffOption Process® MentorsAutism Treatment Center of America®Historic Change AnnouncementSubscribe To Stay In TouchDonate Now!Programs & ServicesProgramsProgram CalendarPrograms by InterestWritten TestimonialsVideo LibraryPrivate Counseling SessionsChallenges & Practical SolutionsResourcesAudioAn Invitation to Change Your LifeBook ExcerptsHappiness HitsInspiring StoriesWebinarsQ&AArticles & DocumentsThe Emotional Well-Being QuizCD DownloadsStoreScholarships & Financial AssistanceOur Mountainside RetreatOur CampusDirectionsDRONE Tour of Our Campus!Upcoming ProgramsContact UsDonateHelp Change Lives-Donate Today!Ways To GiveMonthly Giving
Privacy PolicyOur Commitment to PrivacyThe Option Institute & Fellowship® is committed to your privacy. This notice serves to help you better understand what information we collect, how we use that information, and with whom we may share a limited portion of that information. If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you should contact participant support by email psupport@option.org.We know that you value your personal information, and we strive to protect your privacy as if it were our own. The Option Institute & Fellowship uses of your information is limited to the ways outlined in this notice, except as required by law and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.Information We Collect From YouOnline Contact and Info Requests: If you submit an online request for Option Institute products such as free brochures, or submit a question through a “Contact Us” or “Call-Me” form, we may have to gather additional information from you to respond to your request. Such information will include name, shipping address, telephone number, and email address.Non-Personal Information We Receive Automatically: Like most websites, we utilize cookies. Cookies are a mechanism to remember information about you when you navigate from one web page to another. Our website uses cookies to hold a user’s unique session identifiers, allowing us to serve correct information back to the user. Such information may include your language and currency. Our website cookies do not hold any personally identifiable information. We may use other similar technologies that allow us to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visit to help us better your experience.Lawful Basis For Processing Your DataConsent: We will not process any personal information unless you agree to our Privacy policy and freely give consent to process your information for the purpose of your request.Fulfillment of Requests: We only store and process your information for the purpose of your request. Your information is removed and no longer processed after the request has been fulfilled. If you have also freely consented to receive marketing or promotional communications via a request form or registration form, we will retain your information until you revoke your consent or unsubscribe from receiving those communications via the instructions located at the bottom of all our emails.Sharing of Your DataIf we are required by law – we will disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other legitimate governmental request.We will only share your data with third party service providers such as email services to facilitate fulfillment of your information or contact request. None of your information will be processed or stored by any third party if you choose to revoke your consent or submit a request to be forgotten.We do not share or distribute your information with any other third parties for any purposes other than the purposes you freely consent to.Use Of Information Collected From YouInformation Requests and Customer Service: After submitting information to us via our online forms, your contact information including your email address will be used to respond to that request. After you submit online information requests to us, you may, from time to time, receive email or other communications from us or our service providers with information including information about our upcoming programs or products if you choose to agree to receive those communications. If you do not wish to receive these communications, you are able to opt out of at any time by following the unsubscribe link found in the email.Third-Party Service Providers: We work closely with other companies and individuals to facilitate transactions and better your experience. Examples of third-party service provider services include shipping orders, analyzing data, providing accurate search results and links, affiliate marketing, and newsletters. Any information that we share with a third-party service provider is done so safely, securely, and under a contractual relationship with that provider to protect your data.Promotional events: From time to time, we or a service provider acting on our behalf may use your name, email address, telephone number and/or mailing address to send you information or offers for a program, product or other service we believe to be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive these communications, you are able to opt out of at any time by following the unsubscribe link found in the email.Data Retention PolicyWe maintain a data retention policy to protect your data. Information collected on our website will be retained for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected.How We Secure Your InformationWe are committed to protecting the security of your personal information and to honoring your choices for its intended use. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we strive to maintain physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards. We use industry standard security protocol such as encryption and https security protocol to protect your information. Any time we share your information with a third party consistent with this Privacy Policy, we utilize technological or contractual safeguards in an effort to keep your information safe. While we are confident ordering online is safe and secure, if for any reason you cannot access the secure server or feel uncomfortable ordering online, please feel free to place your order with us by phone at 877-766-7473 or +001-413-229-2100. At any time you wish to opt out of receiving promotional mailings, you may call or email Customer Service.Your RightsAt any time, you can use the following request form http://option.org/privacy-request/ to request any of the following:confirm whether or not personal data about you is being processed;provide you with further details about how we process your personal data;provide you with a copy of any data which we hold about you;withdraw your consent to using your personal information, where we rely on your consent as a legal basis to justify using your personal data;consider any valid objection to the processing of your personal information (including the right to object to processing on grounds related to your particular situation where we are relying on our legitimate interests as a legal basis for processing);request to update or delete personal data which we hold about you;restrict the way that we process your personal data;consider any valid request to transfer your personal data to a third party provider of services (data portability); andWe will consider all requests. However, certain personal information may be exempt from those requests in certain circumstances, which include a need to keep processing information for our legitimate interests or to comply with a legal obligation. If such an exception applies, we will notify you when responding to your request. Please note that we may ask you to provide us with information necessary to confirm your identity before responding.Policy UpdatesWe reserve the right to update the above policy at any time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the updates to this Privacy Policy here and on any other place we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 2080 S. Undermountain Road, Sheffield, MA USA 01257 ParticipantSupport@option.org
US (800) 714-2779 INT. 1 (413) 229-2100 CALL MEOption InstituteSite Map | Privacy PolicyPayment & Cancellation PolicyCopyright © 1998 – 2018 The Option Institute & Fellowship.
All Rights Reserved. A nonprofit, federally tax-exempt charitable organization.
Contact UsCall MeOr send us a message or question and we will get back to you as soon as we can. NameEmailMessageThank You! We will be in contact with you in 1 to 2 business days. x Suzanne PrussPracticing The Option Process for 25 yearsCertified Option Process Mentor-CounselorCertified Son-Rise Program Instructor for 20 yearsMentor Liaison for Certified Option Process Mentor-Counselors world-wide Fun Facts about Suzanne PrussGrowing up in Australia I attended a one-room, one-teacher primary school, ‘Little House on the Prairie’ style.Love traveling: have lived in 6 different countries and love that The Berkshires is now home.Greatest accomplishment: curing my body of Fibromyalgia, Chronic Fatigue, & Lymes Disease.Client Testimonial:Suzanne is a kindred spirit and a powerful teacher.
I love this woman & truly appreciate her (dialogue).
Love the twinkle in her eyes. ~Barbara Bachelder, Pilates trainer, CanadaThis was a profound experience I have never had:
someone listening to me that really cared about my feelings.
Amazing how simple questions can make you think, feel, cry and make you realize things about yourself. ~Patty Hendricks, PAIncredible – I was able to gain so much direction/clarity in my session and I’m thrilled and grateful for my time with her. ~Naomi Webb, Australia
×
Everything we feel, say, and do has a chosen belief which fuels itWe filter all our experiences through our beliefs and mindsets (about ourselves, others, and events around us). These beliefs, in turn, determine how we feel and what we do. Most importantly, people’s beliefs are changeable. We can help you to examine and then re-choose beliefs which fuel comfort, happiness, and the inner strength to overcome life’s challenges.
×
You have your own answersOftentimes, we look for our answers from experts, institutions, the media, and the people around us – everyone but ourselves. We believe that you possess all of your own answers to the personal issues that mark your life. We can teach you to access and rely upon your own internal insight.
×
Happiness Is A ChoiceThough many of us speak as if our emotions happen to us, we believe that they are responses we choose in an effort to take care of ourselves. Misery, fear, anger, distress, anxiety, and discomfort are optional, not inevitable. We can show you how to meet crises and challenges with comfort and ease – and to create personal happiness in a sustainable way.
×
Changing the way you see things changes everythingMost of us think that events in our lives are inherently good or bad, and we can only hope for more good than bad. We give you tools to change your point of view about life events. We have seen, over and over again, that learning to change your perspective on external occurrences changes your entire internal experience – which then changes how you deal with external occurrences.
×
We do not teach “the truth”We do not teach “the truth.” We do not teach “the right way to live.” What we do teach are practical tools, principles, strategies, and perspectives for being, overcoming life’s challenges, and sustaining personal happiness.
×
Authenticity, not people-pleasing, builds close relationships and safetyThroughout our lives, we are taught to say what people want to hear, to mask our true selves, to focus on who others think we should be rather than being who we sincerely are. Most of us see this as safe – and crucial to maintaining our relationships. We see personal authenticity and honesty as the key to feeling safe (because you don’t have to live in fear of being “found out”) and creating close, meaningful relationships (because each person can know and love the other for who they really are).
×
We aren’t the victims we’re taught to beAt every turn, most of us are treated as though we are victims – of our genes, or our upbringing, or our subconscious, or outside events. We have specific self-empowering strategies to enable you to capitalize on your own ultimate capability to be in the driver’s seat in every circumstance.
×
Self-criticism and self-doubt may be “normal” (as in “usual”) but they aren’t “natural” (as in “a necessary part of the human condition”)You are not condemned to live the rest of your life thinking that you are not good enough, that something is wrong with you, that you are not whole, that you are not okay as you are. These are learned beliefs, and we can teach you different, more self-supportive ones. Why? Because we don’t believe that anything is wrong with you, and we do believe that you are okay just the way you are.
×
Being non-judgmental is powerful, not passiveMost of us see making judgments (“that’s terrible,” “he’s mean”) as crucial to our moral compass and our ability to take decisive action. However, we see judgments as leading to discomfort, anger, clouded perceptions, and muddled decision-making. That’s why we help you to drop judgments, thus increasing your focus, decisiveness, and ability to handle crises.
×
Invitation to Change
×
The Option Institute® International Learning & Training Center
×
Stan CohenPracticing and teaching The Option Process since 2003.Certified Option Process Mentor/Counselor, Group Facilitator and TeacherPrevious background: Executive Officer and Member of the Board of Directors for a publicly traded bankFun Facts about Stan:Favorite Place to Be: “On a beach in Punta Cana in the Dominican Republic, overlooking the beautiful white sanded beach in front of the turquoise Caribbean Sea.”One Way He Loves to Spend His Free Time: “Training with my children, as a third degree black belt in Tae Kwon Do.”Testimonials:Great, wonderful enthusiasm, and sense of humor. He expressed amazing interest in all of us. Julia K. McCaughey, Real Estate Salesperson, New YorkStan exudes a calm intensity that gently pushes me to my limits and then some. I felt his wisdom and love through his teaching. Joel Witherspoon, Counselor, North CarolinaThis man has amazing skills! His energy lit up the room. His questions challenged and delighted everyone. We played, we worked and we celebrated our discoveries together. I want more Stan. Mark Lindsay, Boatbuilder, Massachussetts
×
Bryn HoganPracticing The Option Process
since 1994.Executive Director of Autism Treatment Center of AmericaSon-Rise Program Teacher and Teacher Trainer in North America, Europe, and the Middle East.Previous background: Special Education Teacher and Case ManagerFun Facts about Bryn HoganGreatest Accomplishments: “Running my daughter’s Son-Rise Program, adopting my children, healing my body of cardiac health challenge and directing the Autism Treatment Center of America for 15 years.Greatest Realization: That I create my own internal experience and that I could teach others to do the sameFavorite Indulgence: Watching Netflix while I do cardioTestimonials for Bryn HoganBryn is a superb facilitator who delivers her subject brilliantly with humor and style. She is a sincere, genuine person who is sensitive to the mood of the audience. I have learned so much from her in 5 days. A personal message for Bryn: ‘I will be forever indebted to you for everything I have learned. You are a true inspiration!’ Sean Driscoll, Translator, WalesBryn is powerful, sharp, keen-witted, intelligent and fearless. One just knows that Bryn can move mountains and does. She is a powerful facilitator. Laine Jastram, Therapist, TexasHer warmth, her ability to connect, her humor and her love radiated in the room. She’s a dynamic speaker who can also bring you to tears in an instant, because she lets you see her love, and her heart. Barbara Partazana, Insurance, FloridaI have never been in the presence of a more powerful, beautiful, articulate speaker. Oh, and she could easily be a successful stand-up comic. Thank you, thank you, thank you for all you’ve shared this week. I am a better person for having known you. Jill Liebler, Mother/Homemaker, Texas
×
Clyde HabermanPracticing and teaching The Option Process since 1996.Director of Major GiftsCertified Option Process Mentor/Counselor, Group Facilitator and Teacher/TrainerPrevious background: Professional Musician and PerformerFun Facts About Clyde HabermanThe best thing I’ve done for myself this year – take Wide Awake and be a student againA perfect morning: up at 5:30, exercise till 6:30, practice clarinet till 7:30, breakfast and off to the OITestimonials for Clyde HabermanClyde’s relaxed, calming and loving style was an inspiration to me throughout the program. His genuine belief that happiness is a choice was clearly articulated and convincingly put forward. His non directive and inclusive approach towards the group was balanced and effective. Without doubt, a master facilitator. Wayne Thomas, Learning & Development Consultant, EnglandClyde delivers the teachings with great clarity, conviction and fun. …He comes from a place of genuine understanding and humility and invites you to step forward with trust and honesty. He is brilliant at creating a safe learning place that is easeful and profound. Starr Cornell, Administrative Assistant, Great Barrington, MAClyde is nurturing, fun, playful, considerate, poetic and loving. He created a safe environment to explore the inner parts of myself, the shadow-side that was aching to be noticed. Jane Buckle, Director, New YorkClyde is a great teacher and leader. I enjoy the poems he shares, his exuberance and excitement about being here, and being part of our process of authentication. Julia K. McCaughey, Retail Manager, Connecticut
×
Raun KaufmanDirector of Global Education for the Option Institute and the Autism Treatment Center of America™Practicing and teaching The Option Process since 1998.Seminar Leader for Business Executives and Educators in North America and EuropeCertified Option Process Mentor-Counselor, Group Facilitator and Teacher TrainerDegree in Biomedical Ethics, Brown UniversityAdvisory Board Member, United States Autism & Asperger Association (USAAA)Certified Son-Rise Program Teacher and Teacher/TrainerFun Facts about Raun K. Kaufman:What’s your favorite movie? American History X – an earth-shattering movie about race in America, bigotry, personal change, and redemption, that ends with a powerfully gutsy conclusion.Two current projects I am excited about: Conducting studies on The Son-Rise Program to be published in peer-reviewed journals and development of new curriculum for the Institute’s business programs.Testimonials:Raun is a ball of fire and a great spark in our midst. An excellent facilitator, Raun’s rapport with us was unique. He created energy constantly, and I was jazzed every moment with him. Raun is a wise, insightful, articulate philosopher and true humanitarian. Donna Hal, ManagementRaun is energetic, dramatic, wise, articulate, immensely loving and delightful. He kept the group spell-bound. Jane Buckle, Director, New YorkRaun is the most outstanding teacher I have ever encountered. Truly exceptional. Raun has such enthusiasm – it radiates from him. Hilary Farmer, Dyslexia Educational Consultant, England
×
Samahria Lyte KaufmanCo-Founder and Co-Director of the Option Institute.Practicing and teaching The Option Process since 1975.Co-Originator of The Son-Rise Program for children with Autism and developmental challenges.Co-Author of A Sacred Dying.Fun Facts about Samahria:Greatest Accomplishment: “Nurturing my son out of autism.”An Inspiring Book That She Recently Read: Man’s Search for Meaning, by: Viktor E. FranklTestimonials:I bring Samahria my questions, the ones I feel most vulnerable with, and seeing them through her eyes, with humor, compassion, and wisdom, I find the next octave of me. Wendy Musk, Teacher, Newton, CTEnergetic, outrageous, exceptional woman, an absolute inspiration; she embodies everything we can be. Samahria’s energy is so powerful that she fills the whole room and is so giving, loving, and accepting of everybody. It’s like she has a fine tuned radar to know who to go to and how and when to stretch them. Zobeeda Madsen, Son-Rise Mom, SpainI wish I could take this graceful lady home with me! What a bubbly, effervescent wealth of knowledge and experience Samahria is! Tammy Patchell-Evans, Son-Rise Program Mom/Dance Studio Owner, CanadaDelightful. Joyous. Irreverent. Samahria is a fun teacher! Who could be better? She is a gem. Valerie Gilbert, Actress, New York
×
"Bears" Barry Neil KaufmanCo-Founder and Co-Director of the Option Institute.Practicing and teaching The Option Process® since 1975.Author of 12 books on The Option ProcessNoted international speaker, Group Facilitator and teacherCo-Originator of The Son-Rise Program® for children with Autism and developmental challengesFun Facts about Barry (Bears) Neil KaufmanFavorite Indulgence: Starbuck’s Mocha FrappuccinoGreatest Accomplishment: “Taking responsibility for my happiness and unhappiness.”Testimonials for Barry (Bears) Neil KaufmanThe search for peace in the world must start within the human heart and within our own families. Barry Neil Kaufman understands that. By personal example and through his writing and counseling, he gives a compelling vision for the building of inner and outer peace. President Jimmy Carter, Nobel Peace Prize LaureateIf there were a Nobel Prize for love, I’d want the Kaufmans to be the first to receive one. Dr. Wayne Dyer, Author, Change Your Thoughts — Change Your Life: Living the Wisdom of the TaoBarry Neil Kaufman champions making the choice to believe in ourselves, to be hopeful and seize the power of loving ourselves and others. Lou Holtz, Head Football Coach, University of Notre DameInspiring, groundbreaking and visionary. Barry Neil Kaufman’s work is the science of love, compassion and insight which will transform the world. Deepak Chopra M.D., Author, Quantum HealingI have never experienced a more brilliant teacher. Bears consistently puts every participant in the ‘playroom’ and constantly and lovingly gives each of us the opportunity to question ourselves, love ourselves even more, and to find out what our ‘new’ best self is. My love for the man whose courage and curiosity created The Option Institute is only slightly less than my overwhelming gratitude. Shelley Stravitz, Educational Consultant, California
×
Leah Taylor RoyPracticing The Option Process for 14 yearsCertified Option Process Mentor/Counselor, Group Facilitator and TeacherPrevious background: Management Consulting and FinanceFun Facts about Leah Taylor RoyAn Inspiring Book That She Recently Read: The World is Flat, by Thomas L. FriedmanFavorite Types of Cuisine: Moroccan and MediterraneanTestimonials for Leah Taylor Roy:I feel she has a softness and understanding of everyone she comes in contact with. She communicates straight from the heart. Her teachings and messages are amazing. Debbie Mokhlessin, Banker, CaliforniaExcellent bundle of brilliant energy, clarity and curiosity. Excellent dialogue processor! Dennis Dougherty, CEO – Landscape, Mill Valley, CALeah displays a delightful presence. She is open and accepting and loving. She is so accepting and wants the best for you so it is easy to grow in transforming and powerful ways. Patrick Davenport, Venture Capital, Massachusetts
×
Beverly HabermanPracticing The Option Process for 21 yearsSpecial Projects Communications CoordinatorCertified Option Process® Mentor-Counselor, Group Facilitator and Teacher TrainerPrevious Background: Professional Musician and TeacherFun Facts about Beverly:Favorite Pastime: Strolling through the streets of Great Barrington with Clyde as we eat and shop our way through a Saturday afternoon.Greatest Accomplishment: “Learning to stand tall in who I am.”Testimonials:Beverly’s excitement for The Option Process is what got me here! Her continued excitement surrounding what she does here is amazing. I enjoy being around someone who is so passionate. When she walks into the room, I find that I want to hear everything she has to say. Kristine Jones, Interior Designer, New JerseyBeverly is a sweet soul who quietly teaches with confidence and compassion. She passes on her knowledge succinctly and clearly. Her explanation of the Option Process® Dialogue is to the point and easy to understand. Clarity is her trademark. Michael Pearl, Lawyer, England
×
Lauren AstorPracticing Option Process for 19 yearsCertified Option Process Mentor/Counselor since 2001Working at The Option Institute as Mentor/Counselor and Special Projects since 2000Previous Background: NYC Teacher, MA Ed.Founder/owner Manhattan BookstoreFun Facts:Wrote 85 original songs including the hit, Exceptional WomanCooks up an awesome chicken matzho ball soupClient Testimonial:Lauren has been my counselor for over a year and I always, always look forward to our dialogues together every week. She helps me work out the big issues and the little ones and, through it all, she offers the gifts of deep love and acceptance, both quite palpable. When I develop comfort and conviction about something, I can feel her cheering me on. I am pursuing a new career and have had a number of doubts and fears along the way. Our weekly sessions have enabled me to get past each obstacle I encounter. I feel so comfortable and safe with Lauren that I have discussed just about every aspect of my life with her! Lauren is a gem, a jewel, a precious gift to me and others. ~Abigail L. Austin, TXI have worked with two other therapists, but our work together was by far, the most effective, rapid and so easy.
Although we never met in person, I instantly felt comfortable. Your gentle, but probing questions helped me breakthrough my deepest circular and unhappy thinking patterns. I now have tools to use for myself and I see so many situations differently.
You have given me the insight for how I make my world.
Thank you for holding up that mirror. I finally feel more grounded and responsible for myself than ever. I will certainly recommend you to everyone. I’m so thankful! ~Julie C. New York, NYThere have been areas of my life where I have felt stuck.
I have tried yoga, therapy, mediation and wine and I just couldn’t move past the psychological barrier.
Your methods, compassion, and generosity have helped me see things from a brand new perspective.
This has been freeing and is helping me move to a whole new chapter in my life. ~Elizabeth B. Millbrook, NY
×
Zoe ZappaSenior adult program counselorPracticing The Option Process for 22 yearsUsed to be an operating room scrub nurse3 children – 30, 26 and 24 (all of them take programs here)Fun Facts about ZoeGreatest Accomplishments: When I realized that I am fully responsible for what I think and feel and moving from the mountains of Colorado to work at The Option Instituteto support others with their journey to personal happiness.Favorite pastime: Walking in nature – collecting rocks, wood, feathers and interesting bugs, and surrounding my life with nature.
×
Dane GriffithDirector of Administrative ServicesWorking at the Option Institute for 15 yearsPrevious Background: Engineering ManagementCurrent Interest: Holistic NutritionFun Facts about DaneFavorite place to be: At my home in Sheffield, on the deck, in a lounge chair next to Liz, dogs playing in the yard, tea mug in hand, deep blue sky with white puffy clouds overhead, nowhere to go and nothing to do – it doesn’t get any better than this!Favorite movie: Lord of the Rings Trilogy
×
Jan-Marie GundackerSon-Rise Program Senior Program AdvisorsPracticing The Option Process for 15 yearsPrevious background: executive director and development director of nonprofit agencies feeding the hungry and teaching adults to read; counselor and coach; published writer.Fun Facts about Jan-MarieFavorite place to be: walking the beach and boards of the Jersey Shore talking to God and basking in the joyful, exquisite beauty of our world.Greatest Accomplishments: my son and daughter, my two biggest miracles; learning to love by watching my mother; seeing the gifts in cancer, twice.
× Dear Donor,Jeannie Reid was searching for answers to the challenges she and her family were facing. Jeannie and her husband Stuart’s son, Carson, had been diagnosed with Pervasive Developmental Disorder, a condition on the Autism spectrum. For Carson that meant being completely involved in obsessive behaviors and only using minimal words to identify objects, as well as frequently and completely melting down.Soon after, Jeannie found the book, “Son-Rise: The Miracle Continues” and when she read it, she KNEW she had found what she was looking for. She began using some of the Son-Rise techniques described in the book on her own until she was able to come to The Autism Treatment Center of America for the Son-Rise Program Start-Up. As she put into practice what she learned there, Carson’s world was opening up. Today Carson is attending a Montessori school as a 'typical' student and functioning at or above typical grade level, being fully verbal and conversational, and very interested in learning about the world and interacting as much as possible with other people. He is even taking swim lessons at the local YMCA and doing great!“It has been wonderful to get, and stay connected with other people and Son-Rise parents from all over the world. My son’s progress had already come very far, but now I truly believe we can go all the way!”Jeannie wrote.Stuart Reid then attended the Empower Yourself course and brought home a new sense of clarity, balance and personal power. He shared his new empowerment with Jeannie and she in turn gained in confidence, strength and enthusiasm. Their own relationship began to flourish anew, as well. Life-altering changes were happening for Jeannie and her family.Jeannie journeyed again to Sheffield, this time for the Fearless course at The Option Institute to help her recognize and overcome her personal obstacles. Jeannie wanted to continue her amazing journey as she had found using the techniques she learned in The Son-Rise Program and in Fearless had absolutely changed the lives of everyone in her family.But, because the Reids’ finances had been seriously stretched by then, their next steps were put on hold. Then an amazing event changed everything. Jeannie’s college roommate and lifelong friend decided to start a Son-Rise Program scholarship fund for people from the Cleveland area. Since then Jeannie has been able to move ahead with her courses, taking Radical Authenticity, Son-Rise Maximum Impact and Son-Rise Wide Awake ... and eventually she became a Certified Group Facilitator.Jeannie Reid’s story is about wanting BIG and making it happen. She is about to embark on her renewed private practice as an art therapist, and plans to be a super advocate for The Son-Rise Program in her area. Her wonderful new life is a product of her persistence and belief, and of the wheels she helped set in motion for others when her friends learned of how she and her family had been impacted by The Son-Rise Program.“I know I will be able to give back by helping others, and that will be the top of my personal mountain! Thank you to everyone who donates! You are making a big difference in the world!Jeannie Reid Dear DonorTwo years ago, Antonio's kindergarten teacher told us something was not quite right with our little boy. He was not socializing, he somersaulted all the time and hardly spoke at all. At the time I was working for a municipality close to Florence, Italy and basically I had nothing left after seeing to basic necessities.In the meantime, I looked up Autism with Google and as I was also looking for happiness and personal growth, I was guided to The Option Institute, thence the Autism Treatment Center of America. I read up as much as I could and started trying to apply the “Happiness is a Choice” suggestions. I'm not quite good at it but it has helped me with attitude, and everything else that seemed trying is really different after all this.When I decided to come for The Son-Rise Program Start-Up, I really had little or no money to pay for it. I spoke to my friends, old and new. My mother helped me, friends I thought couldn't [help] tried their very best and the scholarship did the rest.What the scholarship did was give a HUGE boost to my fundraising. About six friends contributed the rest, at the travel agency a very kind lady who I may now call a friend helped me some more. I am overwhelmed with gratefulness. Here I am, happy to have attended the Start-Up program and looking forward to learning more and praying to God for guidance.So the gist of the matter is, I am a happy mum who hopes to implement a wonderful relationship with her child and is riding a not so easy moment with lots of hope in her heart and THANK YOU is not enough for what I feel. I still remember William's words, “If you do what you've always done, you will get what you've always got.” Now I'm trying to do different, bit by bit, day by day. I feel the difference already.About Antonio ... we are going on with the Italian program and I play with Antonio after school in a quiet room in the house. Knowing what the little guy is exposed to (he's always putting his fingers in his ears and he seems to have problems with too much light in his eyes), I find him very brave as he bears it tolerably. Drums a lot to digest it all.When we went to the doctor, just weeks after starting the program at home, she told me that she found him more attentive. His attention span has increased. He is also tagging or pulling at one's arm when looking for attention. The child psychologist last Saturday reported the same thing and what's more, my son has always required that I enter the room, hence assisting in every session. Well, this time he went in along with the doctor and told me, “See you later.”At school, his teacher who speaks English as well, read up and watched my DVD (Kyle’s Journey, Jade and “I want my little boy back”). Now she's changing, bit by bit and I do appreciate that very much. He seems to be OK with her and actually sent me away from class this morning, again telling me, “See you later.”He is now ONE HUGE GREENLIGHT and I'm hoping to be able to really have volunteers (still looking), raise funds and settle down to business.God bless,Jackline Dear Donor,I am the mother of three children, all on the Autism Spectrum. Before I heard of the Son-Rise Program and the Option Institute, I was a desperate, angry and depressed person…. I was on Anti-depressants, sleeping multiple hours of the day, and for a period of time, using alcohol to run away from my pain.Then I heard of the Son-Rise Program. I called to find out more about it and thought “this if for me!” But I could not afford it. You see raising one child with Autism is very expensive but raising three is just outrageously expensive with all the therapies and dietary interventions that we were doing.But I was offered a full scholarship to the SRSU program. I have since attended all of the Son-Rise Programs and many of the Personal Growth programs offered by the Option Institute.  Each time I have been given a scholarship and each time I go I learn more about who I am and I change for the better each and every time.  Because of your most generous support, my children are recovering from Autism, I have found happiness in my life!  I am no longer on anti-depressants and I have so much more energy.YOU are the reason that my family is in recovery. It is because of YOU that my oldest son now is enjoying school.  YOU are the reason my second son is speaking. YOU are the reason my daughter is no longer as rigid and controlling as she once was.  Thank you does not even begin to cover how much gratitude I have for you.  I thank God every day for you and I do not even know you.Please know that you are changing lives with your donation to ATCA and the OI.  It is because of you that every day people are getting the help that they need. Thank you, thank you and thank you!With so much love,Kerry Rihtar
